Finding Aid for the Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Brainard Bartwell Cheney and Frances Neel Cheney Papers File Listing
  - Writings, Research and Outlines, Articles
    - An Experiment in Teaching Bibliography of the Social Sciences RQ Summer 1971 (Off Prints, Correspondence and Response) (Box 57, File 1)
    - Assorted Articles (All Published) (Box 57, File 2)
    - Assorted Articles (All Published) (Box 57, File 3)
    - Books for the General Reader (Guy R. Lyle) (Box 57, File 4)
    - Dictionary of American Library Biography, Margaret Hutchins (Box 57, File 5)
    - Encyclopedias for Encyclopedia of Library and Information Sciences (Box 57, File 6)
    - Encyclopedias for Encyclopedia of Library and Information Sciences (Box 57, File 7)
    - Knowing the World We Live In: Sources of Geographical Information (Box 57, File 8)
    - Library: Dictionary of Library Associations for Encyclopedia Americana, 1971 (Box 57, File 9)
    - Libraries for the New International Year Book, Events of, 1964 (Box 57, File 10)
    - Present State of Reference Work in the South (Box 57, File 11)
    - Untitled Outline and Draft (Censorship) Writings, Research and Outlines, Book Manuscripts (Box 57, File 12)
    - An Annotated List of Selected Japanese Reference Materials. Ed. By Frances Neel Cheney and Yukiko Monji (Box 57, File 13)
    - Fundamental Reference Service 2nd Ed- Chapter 1 (Box 57, File 14)
    - Fundamental Reference Service 2nd Ed- Chapter 2 (Box 57, File 15)
    - Fundamental Reference Service 2nd Ed- Chapter 3 (Box 57, File 16)
    - Fundamental Reference Service 2nd Ed- Chapter 4 (Box 57, File 17)
    - Fundamental Reference Service 2nd Ed- Chapter 5 (Box 57, File 18)
    - Fundamental Reference Service 2nd Edition - Article Additions (Box 58, File 1)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 58, File 2)
    - Sources of Information in the Humanities, Contributor Correspondence, 1973-1975 (Box 58, File 3)
  - Writings, Research and Outlines, Publications
    - 1955-1959 (Box 58, File 4)
    - 1961-1963 (Box 58, File 5)
    - 1964-1967 (Box 58, File 6)
  - Writings, Research and Outlines, Reviews
    - American Educator Encyclopedia (Box 58, File 7)
    - Assorted (Box 58, File 8)
    - Assorted (Box 58, File 9)
    - Assorted (Box 58, File 10)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, September 1945-December 1945 (Box 58, File 11)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1946-December 1946 (Box 58, File 12)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1947-December 1947 (Box 58, File 13)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1948-December 1948 (Box 58, File 14)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1949-December 1949 (Box 59, File 1)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1950-December 1950 (Box 59, File 2)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1951-December 1951 (Missing April 1951) (Box 59, File 3)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1964-December 1964 (Box 59, File 4)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1965-December 1965 (Box 59, File 5)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1966-December 1966 (Box 59, File 6)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1967-December 1967 (Box 59, File 7)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin, January 1968-June 1968 (Box 59, File 8)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1947 (Box 59, File 9)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1963-1972 (Box 59, File 10)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1963-1972 Continued (Box 59, File 11)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1956-1960 (Box 60, File 1)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1961-1963 (Box 60, File 2)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1964-1966 (Box 60, File 3)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1968-1971 (Box 60, File 4)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 60, File 5)
    - Current Reference Books, Wilson Bulletin- Titles Reviewed 195?, Dec 1967 (Box 60, File 6)
    - Golden Book Encyclopedia Correspondence (Box 60, File 7)
    - Guzman, Jessie Parkhurst- Negro YearBook, 1947 (Box 60, File 8)
    - Harriman, Phillip Lawrence- The New Dictionary of Psychology, 1947 (Box 60, File 8)
    - Public Affairs Press- American Names, 1947 (Box 60, File 8)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books- Outgoing Correspondence (Box 60, File 9)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books- Incoming Correspondence (Box 60, File 10)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books- Incoming Correspondence (J. Marion Kimbrough) (Box 60, File 11)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books-November, December 1972 (Box 60, File 12)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, January-March 1973 (Box 61, File 1)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, April-June 1973 (Box 61, File 2)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, July-August 1973 (Box 61, File 3)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, September-December 1973 (Box 61, File 4)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, January-March 1974 (Box 61, File 5)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, April-June 1974 (Box 61, File 6)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, July-September 1974 (Box 61, File 7)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, October-December 1974 (Box 61, File 8)
    - Reference Services Review, Recent Reference Books, January-March 1975 (Box 61, File 9)
  - Writings, Research and Outlines, Speeches
    - October 28, 1950-April 29, 1953 (Box 61, File 10)
    - October 8 and 9 1953-October 23, 1953 (Box 61, File 11)
    - at the Newman Club for Father Ryan Students and November 17, 1953 for the Vanderbilt Woman’s Club “The Vanderbilt of Japan”, November 8, 1953 (Box 61, File 12)
    - for Peabody Faculty Lecture, “Books and Reading in the Modern World”, July 7, 1954 (Box 61, File 13)
    - “Knowledge- Strength of a Free People” at Arkansas Library Association, October 18, 1954 (Box 61, File 14)
    - for Arkansas Library Association, October 18 and 19 1954 (Box 61, File 15)
    - College Libraries at Mississippi Library Association, October 22, 1954 (Box 61, File 16)
    - The High School Library for Carnegie Fellows at Peabody, April 6, 1955 (Box 61, File 17)
    - “Current Library Problems” Panel –“Personnel” Library Conference at Oak Ridge, Tennessee, April 15, 1955 (Box 62, File 1)
    - “Introduction and Discussion of “The Common Heritage” Film Kansas Rural Reading Conference, November 15, 1955 (Box 62, File 2)
    - California Library Association, November 2, 1956 (Box 62, File 3)
    - to the Colonna Club, Nashville, “The Romantic Era”, December 9, 1969 (Box 62, File 4)
    - to the Mid-South Catholic Librarians Association, “The Next Decade”, February 21, 1970 (Box 62, File 5)
    - to SELA Luncheon on Library Education and Manpower, Atlanta Introduction for Lester Asheim, November 4, 1970 (Box 62, File 6)
    - Banquet Speaker- Southern Regional Group of the Medical Library Association, October 1, 1971 (Box 62, File 7)
    - to Medical Library Association, Nashville, “Library Humor”, October 6, 1971 (Box 62, File 8)
    - to the Mississippi Library Association, “Future of Reference Service”, October 21, 1971 (Box 62, File 9)
    - to University of Kentucky Colloquium, College of Library Science, “Tell Me Where Is Reference Bred?”, November 15, 1971 (Box 62, File 10)
    - to Western Kentucky State University Library Science Department, “Reference/Information Services For the 70’s”, February 29, 1972 (Box 62, File 11)
    - “Reference Service in the 70’s Louisiana Library Association, March 24, 1972 (Box 62, File 12)
    - to Florida Library Association, “State of Library Education”, April 27, 1972 (Box 62, File 13)
    - to Villanova University Library Science Department, “Reference Book Reviewing”, April 30, 1972 (Box 62, File 14)
    - to Wednesday Club, Nashville, “Literature of the 20’s”, May 24, 1972 (Box 62, File 15)
    - to Bookclub, Nashville (Culture Vultures), “Nietzsche”, February 8, 1973 (Box 62, File 16)
    - to Texas Library Association, also to the Arkansas College Librarians and Undergraduate Library Science Teachers on April 27, 1973, “The Gentle Art of Reference Book Reviewing”, November 2, 1974 (Box 62, File 17)
    - to the Catholic Library Association and Modified on May 6, 1974 for Elizabeth Findly’s retirement, “The Librarian as Bookman”, April 18, 1974 (Box 63, File 1)
    - to Library Science Instructors, Arkansas, “Undergraduate Library Education”, April 27 and 28, 1974 (Box 63, File 2)
    - JUL Workshop, July 29, 1974 (Box 63, File 3)
    - to Kentucky Library Association (also given April 19, 1967), “Pop Docs”, October 26, 1974 (Box 63, File 4)
    - to Smyrna Senior Citizens, “Dictionaries- Quotations”, 1976 (Box 63, File 5)
    - to Oklahoma Library Association Reference Division, “What’s Ahead for Reference Service?”, March 25, 1976 (Box 63, File 6)
    - to Peabody Library School Students, “Random Remarks”, April 3, 1978 (Box 63, File 7)
    - to Clarksville Area Library Association, “Special Collections in the Southeast”, April 13, 1978 (Box 63, File 8)
    - at WNBA Dinner, “Tribute to Mary Stahlman Douglas”, June 3, 1978 (Box 63, File 9)
    - to Bookclub, Nashville, “Blues”, November 9, 1978 (Box 63, File 10)
    - to University School English Class, “Humor in Southeastern Short Story Writers”, 1979 (Box 63, File 11)
    - to Rutherford County DAR’s and Later to Smyrna Rotary Club, “Americas Origins”, February 23, 1979 (Box 63, File 12)
    - to Peabody Library School Students, “Southern Libraries in the Depression of the 1930’s”, April 5, 1979 (Box 63, File 13)
    - to Peabody Library School Students, “On Occasion of W. Williams Leaving”, August 7, 1979 (Box 63, File 14)
    - “Eudora Welty” to the Women’s Club, Murfreesboro, TN, March 19, 1981 (Box 63, File 15)
    - to University of Tennessee Lectures,“Writers as Readers”, May 19, 1981 (Box 63, File 16)
    - to Peabody Library School Students and Alumni, “Writers as Readers”, October 28, 1981 (Box 63, File 17)
    - to Peabody Library School Alumni Reunion, “Writers as Readers”, May 29, 1982 (Box 63, File 18)
    - to Friends of the Library “Peabody Collection of Books on Children”, August 29, 1982 (Box 63, File 19)
    - Emergence of Modern China (Box 63, File 20)
  - Academic Library Materials
    - Columbia University—Historical and Biographical Study of the Administrative Departments of the State of Tennessee, (1938) (Box 63, File 21)
    - Columbia University—School of Library Service, Syllabus, 1938 (Box 63, File 22)
    - Japan Library School—Assorted Materials (Box 63, File 23)
    - Japan Library School—Assorted Materials (Box 63, File 24)
    - Japan Library School—Lib. 120: Informational and Biographical Sources and Materials (Box 64, File 1)
    - Japan Library School—Lib. 130: Book Selection and Reader’s Advisory Service (Box 64, File 2)
    - Japan Library School—Lib. 190: Education for Librarianship: The Library School and its Students (Box 64, File 3)
    - Japan Library School—Bibliography of Library Sciences in Japan (Box 64, File 4)
    - Japan Library School—Correspondence Regarding Frances Neel Cheney going to Japan (Box 64, File 5)
    - Japan Library School—Japanese Impressions of American Libraries (Box 64, File 6)
    - Japan Library School—Japanese Library History (Box 64, File 7)
    - Japan Library School—Keio University (Box 64, File 8)
    - Japan Library School—Keio University (Box 64, File 9)
    - Japan Library School—Library Profession in Japan (Box 64, File 10)
    - Japan Library School—National Diet Library (Box 64, File 11)
    - Japan Library School—Reading Guidance (Box 64, File 12)
    - Japan Library School—Reference Books (Box 64, File 13)
    - Japan Library School—Reference Service, Bibliography of Articles on Reference Works in Japanese Journals Beginning in, 1924 (Box 64, File 14)
    - Japan Library School—Reference Service (Box 65, File 1)
    - Japan Library School—Reference Service (Box 65, File 2)
    - Japan Library School—Reference Service Lectures (Box 65, File 3)
    - Japan Library School—School Libraries (Box 65, File 4)
    - Japan Library School—Students (Box 65, File 5)
    - Japan Library School—Students (Box 65, File 6)
    - Japan Library School—Students (Box 65, File 7)
    - Japan Library School—Workshops (Box 65, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School—Assorted (Box 65, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Assorted (Box 65, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Automation and Information Retrieval, Publications and Essay (Box 65, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Automation and Information Retrieval, Publications (Box 66, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Encyclopedia (Box 66, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Encyclopedia (Box 66, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Encyclopedia (Box 66, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Encyclopedia (Box 66, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Encyclopedia Catholic Encyclopedia for School and Home (Box 66, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Encyclopedia Britannica 3, Great Soviet Encyclopedia in English Translation (Box 66, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 220 Introduction to Bibliography (Box 66, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 221 Selection and Acquisition of Library Materials (Box 66, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 322 Bibliography of the Humanities, Course Description (Box 66, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School— Course Materials 322 Literature (Box 66, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 406 Bibliography (Box 66, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 415 Reference and Bibliography (Box 66, File 13)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials Reference and Bibliography, Publications (Box 66, File 14)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417 Book Selection (Box 67, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P Acquisition of Library Materials (Book Selection) Course Outline and Schedule, Fall 1960 (Box 67, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P, Assorted (Box 67, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417 Student Comment, Summer 1955 (Box 67, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P Student Reports (Box 67, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P I. Reader (Box 67, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P I. C. Readability (Box 67, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P II Library Resources (Box 67, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III Forms of Publication, their Selection for Use (Box 67, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A Books (Box 67, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.2 Bookselling and Distribution of Print (Box 67, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.2 Bookselling and Distribution of Print (Box 67, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.3 Censorship (Box 67, File 13)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.3 Censorship (Box 68, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.3 Censorship (Box 68, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.3 Censorship (Box 68, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.3 Censorship (Box 68, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.3 Censorship (Box 68, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.4 Editions, Series and Translations (The Impact of the Paperbound) (Box 68, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.5 Standard General Aids to Selection (Box 69, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.5.a Booktrade Tools as Selection Aids (Subject Indexes) (Box 69, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.5.b Trade Bibliographies (as Bibliographic Record) (Box 69, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.5.b Trade Bibliographies (as Bibliographic Record) (Box 69, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.5.c Current Reviews, Periodicals and Indexes (Box 69, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.6.a The Book Review (Box 69, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.7 General Problems of Book Selection (Box 69, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.7.a Selection for the School Library (Box 69, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.7.b Selection for the College Library (Box 69, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.7.c Selection for the Public Library (Box 70, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.A.7.d Selection for the Special Group (Box 70, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.B Periodicals and Newspapers (Box 70, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.B Periodicals and Newspapers (Box 70, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 417P III.B.1 General Problems of Selection (Box 70, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Syllabus, Winter 1958 (Box 70, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit IV Political Science Correspondence, Notes, and Outlines (Box 70, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit IV Political Science Student Paper (Box 70, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit IV Political Science Publications, 1936-1959 (Box 70, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit IV Political Science Publications, 1960-1961 (Box 70, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit V Sociology and Social Welfare Correspondence, Notes, and Essays (Box 70, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit V Sociology and Social Welfare Publications, 1948-1956 (Box 70, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit V Sociology and Social Welfare Publications, 1958-1961 (Box 71, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VI Economics and Business Correspondence, Notes, and Essays (Box 71, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VI Economics and Business Publications, 1947-1955 (Box 71, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VI Economics and Business Publications, 1956-1959 (Box 71, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VI Economics and Business Publications, 1960-1961, and Undated (Box 71, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VII Psychology and Education Correspondence and Essays (Box 71, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VII Psychology and Education Notes (Box 71, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VII Psychology and Education Student Work (Box 71, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VII Psychology and Education Publication, 1947-1956 (Box 72, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502B Bibliography of the Social Sciences Unit VII Psychology and Education Publications, 1957- 1960 and Undated (Box 72, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Course Syllabus Pre-1962 (Box 72, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Course Syllabus 1962 and Notes (Box 72, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Course Syllabus 1962 with additions for later version (Box 72, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences DePierri- Syllabus from 1962 with Notes (Box 72, File 6)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Outline, Spring 1965 (Box 72, File 7)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences 1959 and 1960 Visiting Lectures and Field Trips Schedule, Notes and Comments for Summer 1961 Course Taught by J. H. Lancaster and Correspondence with Visiting Lecturers (Box 72, File 8)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Tests, Quizzes, Mid-Term Exams and Final Exams Sporadic from, Spring 1951- Spring 1962 (Box 72, File 9)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Summer 1963, DePierri Final Exams (Box 72, File 10)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Tests, Quizzes, Mid-Term Exams and Final Exams Sporadic from Spring 1964, Spring 1966 and Undated (Box 72, File 11)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences Film and Xerography, including Correspondence (Box 72, File 12)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences U.S. Atomic Energy Commission Motion Picture Film Library Catalogue, January 1961, September 1961 and January 1964 (Box 72, File 13)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 4. Government Publications Correspondence, Notes, and Publications, 1959-1960 (Box 72, File 14)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 4. Government Publications- Publications, 1961-1962 (Box 73, File 1)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 4. Government Publications- Publications 1962-1966 and Undated (Box 73, File 2)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 5. Publications of Associations Institutions and Other Agencies, 1962-1963 (Box 73, File 3)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 5. Publications of Associations Institutions and Other Agencies 1964 and Undated (Box 73, File 4)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 6. Journals (Box 73, File 5)
    - Peabody Library School-- Course Materials 502C Bibliography of the Sciences I. Introduction G. The Literature of Science 11. Popular Books (Box 73, File 6)